本可伟大
翻译
零九/presisco
校对
presisco
特效
presicso
压制
presisco
史蒂文？
Steven.
嗨
Hi.
为什么我们不再准备钻头了？
Why did we stop working on the drill?
为什么他们就坐在那里，无所事事？
Why are they just sitting there, looking at nothing?!
我们辛苦工作了，
We worked hard,
自然应该放松一下
and we deserve to take it easy for a little bit.
我是指，看看这风景吧！
I mean, just look at that view!
真的非常漂亮！
It's beautiful!
这一切都将被融合簇炸为虚无
It's going to be blown to oblivion by the cluster
如果我们不回去工作的话
if we don't get back to work!
努力工作很重要，
Working hard is important,
但享受生活也很重要啊！
but feeling good is important, too!
你在说什么？！
What are you talking about?!
嘿-呲-！
Hey -- bzzzz!
那是什么，一个C音？
What is that, a -- a "c"?
电钻吗？
The drill?
没错
Yeah!
我的天！
Oh my gosh!
现在这是音乐了！
Now it's music!
音乐？
Music?
没错，是音乐
Yeah, it's music.
像这个...
Like this...
do-re-mi-fa-so-la-ti-do
♪ Do re mi fa so LA ti do ♪
do-mi-so-do?
Do mi so do.
这不错吧？
♪ Isn't it pretty?
这真是太简单了
That's exceedingly simple.
do-mi-so-ti
Do mi so ti.
我们在制作音乐
♪ We're making music
有什么意义吗？
what is the point?
你有没在制作任何东西
You're not making anything.
那么，如果这不算东西，那为什么听起来如此之好？
Well, if it isn't anything, then why does it sound so good?
我猜这只是乐趣而已
I suppose it's just interest.
do-mi-so-do...
Do mi so do...
缺少实质与意义，是假想的模式
Devoid of substance or purpose. A hypothetical pattern.
do-mi-so-ti
Do mi so ti...
为了完成它所带来的满足！
For the satisfaction of bringing it to completion!
当然！
Sure!
do-mi-so-ti...
Do mi so ti...
毫无意义的兴趣？
Interest without meaning?
缺少问题的答案？
Solutions without problems?
然后你只需要增加歌词
And then you just add words.
这是一个我在制作的歌曲...
Here's one I've been working on...
生与死与爱与新生
♪ Life and death and love and birth ♪
和平与纷争在这地球
♪ and peace and war on the planet earth ♪
有什么能够比得上
♪ is there anything that's worth more ♪
和平与爱在这地球
♪ than peace and love on the planet earth? ♪
快来跟我一起唱
♪ Come on and sing it with me
唱？
♪ sing?
歌词关系着答案
♪ The words relate to the key
答案？
♪ key?
若是个规律，若是个规律
♪ If it's a pattern, if it's a pattern ♪
那只需跟着我唱
♪ then just repeat after me ♪
生与死与爱与新生
♪ life and death and love and birth ♪
现在唱mi-fa mi-mi fa mi ti la
Now you sing ♪ mi, fa mi, mi fa mi ti LA ♪
和平与纷争在这地球
♪ and peace and war on the planet earth ♪
对，对，就这样！
Yes, yes, that's it!
那真简单
That's so easy.
对，但这就是有趣的地方
Yeah, but that's what's fun about it.
你该写点什么，你该写首歌！
You should write something. You should write a song!
关于什么？
About what?
你所想的事情
Whatever you're thinking.
我们已经在此
♪ I guess we're already here
我们已经已明晰
♪ I guess we already know
我们都有所畏惧
♪ we've all got something to fear ♪
我们都无处可归
♪ we've all got nowhere to go
我想你们都疯
♪ I think you're all insane
但我也如此
♪ but I guess I am, too
无人例外，如果与你们困在地球
♪ anybody would be if they were stuck on earth with you ♪
对！
Yes!
生与死与爱与新生
♪ Life and death and love and birth and ♪
♪ life and death and love and birth and ♪
生与死与爱与新生
♪ life and death and love and birth ♪
和平与纷争在这地球
♪ and peace and war on the planet earth ♪
有什么能够比得上
♪ is there anything that's worth more ♪
和平与爱在这地球？
♪ than peace and love on the planet earth? ♪
喔！
Whoa!
干的不错
Nice work.
我们真的做到了，对吧？
We really did it, huh?
我们？
We?
哦，等等，我得检查点东西！
Oh, wait. I need to check something!
她人变了好多！
She's come so far!
感觉就像昨天她还想搞死我们
It feels like yesterday she was trying to kill us.
不，不，那是好几周之前
No, no, that was several weeks ago.
坐标！
Coordinates!
我们还需要融合簇的具体坐标
We still need the cluster's exact coordinates
才能开钻！
in order to drill!
有个钻石基地可能包含这个信息，
There's a diamond base that may hold that information,
但前往那里将会非常困难
but getting there is going to be difficult.
怎么会？
How come?
因为那里无法通过传送台到达，而且它在...
Because it's not accessible by warp pad, and it's on...
月球？！
The moon?!
没错，史蒂文，月球
Yeah, Steven, the moon.
狮子，你给我们制造一个通向月球的超级传送吗？
Lion, can you make us a special super warp to the moon?
来吧，狮子！
Come on, Lion!
我们必须做这个才能阻止融合簇！
We got to do this to stop the cluster!
如果我们做不到，那就不不会有什么地球了！
If we don't, there's gonna be no more earth!
不会有朋友间的快乐时光！
No more fun times with your pals!
不会有狮子棒棒糖？
No more Lion Lickers?
不会有懒觉了？
No more naps?
看来是“懒觉”
Guess it was "naps."
挺酷的，对吧？！
Pretty cool, right?!
上，狮子，上！
Go, Lion, go!
狮子！你还好吗，伙计？
Lion! Are you okay, bud?
让我从这个毛茸茸的怪胎里出来-呃！嗷！
Get me out of this furry freak -- ugh! Ow!
哦，狮子，你为自己赢得了一周的懒觉！
Aw, Lion, you've earned your naps for the week!
我们做到了
We made it.
这看起来不像是月球啊
It doesn't look like the moon.
嘿，看这里，我觉得这是个门！
Hey, look over here. I think it's a door!
呃...对！
Uh...Yep!
我们在月球上！
We on the moon!
紫晶，求求你别把我们吸到太空中了！
Amethyst, please don't blow us into space!
喔！
Whoa!
看看我！
Look at me!
我是月球小子！
I'm a moon boy!
哈哈！好的，月球小子！
Ha ha! All right, moon boy!
月球小子，四重后空翻！
Moon boy, quadruple backflip!
嘿！
Hey!
我没什么就不能是月球小子？
Why can't I be a moon boy?
我们是宝石人
We're gems.
我们是太空种族
We're a space-faring race
我们被设计为便于征服其他世界的！
designed to conquer other worlds!
我们的身体形态会自动根据
Our physical forms adjust automatically
任何星球的重力进行调整！
to the gravity of any planetoid!
噢，真矬！
Aw, lame!
我有天在月球瞎蹦
♪ I was bouncing on the moon one day ♪
此处曲调源自“Fountain in the Park”
与尤金·塞尔南和哈里森·施密特1972年阿波罗17号舱外活动中所唱的类似
呃？
Huh?
嘿，橄榄石，那应该是谁？
Hey, Peridot, who is this supposed to be?
那是蓝钻石！
It's blue diamond!
等等，她们都在这里？
Wait. Are they all here?
啊，对！
Ah, yes!
她在那！
There she is!
谁？
Who?
请看，黄钻石！
Behold, yellow diamond!
她很雄伟吧？
Isn't she magnificent?
喔！
Wow!
那么，钻石是什么？
So, who are the diamonds anyway?
她们看起来很重要！
They seem like a big deal!
你在开玩笑吗？
Are you joking me?
钻石是宝石人们的母亲！
The diamonds are the gem matriarchs!
她们一起组成了伟大的钻石政权
Together they make up the great diamond authority
掌管着母世界与所有偏远的殖民地！
that governs homeworld and all the outlying colonies!
我们只为服务她们！
We live to serve them!
我-我指，我们最初的目的是服务她们
I -- I mean, we were all made to serve them
只是一部分人不再如此
even though some of us don't anymore.
嘿，我觉得那是控制界面！
Hey, I think that's a control surface over there!
我们看看吧！
Let's take a look!
好啊！
Yeah!
我感觉这样才对
I think this is right.
这里的材料与周围的石头不同
The material is different from the surrounding stone.
我感觉如果我...这么做！
I think if I just do...This!
这真是太神奇了！
This is so incredible!
只有精英中的精英才能深入这里
Only the most elite of the elite can enter these sanctums.
我们真的是在沿着钻石们的足迹！
We are literally walking in the footsteps of the diamonds.
她们肯定非常喜欢台阶
They must really like stairs.
嘿，这是什么房间？
Hey, what's this room?
这不是我们此行的目的
It's not what we came for.
我们能快点吗？这地方让我不爽
Can we hurry it up? This place gives me the creeps.
我们真的在月球上了！
We really are on the moon!
哦，我的天哪！
Oh, my goodness!
这看起来还是全新的！
This looks like it could be brand-new!
我是指，按现在的标准这是古董，
I mean, it's a relic by today's standards,
但，妈呀，这真是如此优雅，
but, golly, it's so elegant,
如此简洁，如此完美！
so simple, so perfect!
那么，你能打开它吗？
So, how do you turn it on?
我不会
I have no idea.
嘿，这有个发光的手形界面哎！
Hey, it's got one of those glowy hand dealies!
你不能坐在那里！
You can't sit there!
为什么不？这真的很酷！
Why not? It's really cool!
那个椅子只为了给最尊贵的宝石人！
That chair is only for the most elite gems!
你不能随便坐到精英该坐的地方！
You can't go around sitting where an elite would sit!
不过，她们现在不在，对吧？
Well, they aren't here now, right?
嘿，这个玩意是做什么的？
Hey, what's this doodad for?
把它放回去！
Put that back!
嗯，好吧，我们看看
Hmm, okay, let's see here.
开始吧
There we go.
这是个非常古老的系统
This is a really old system.
得找到正确的文件...
Gotta find the right file...
啊哈！
Aha!
融合簇，融合簇，你在哪里，融合簇？
Cluster, cluster, where are you, cluster?
啊哈！
Aha!
这里是注入点！
There's the insertion point!
看来是在切面九的第二幼儿园
Looks like the beta kindergarten in facet nine.
那是两个中较小的那个，
It's the smaller of the two,
一点不如你出生的那个出色，紫晶！
not nearly as impressive as yours, Amethyst!
呃，谢谢？
Uh, thanks?
但融合簇现在在哪呢？
But where is the cluster now?
等下
Hang on.
它在那！
There it is!
它深深的嵌入了地幔之中
It's embedded deep in the mantle.
相对于谷仓，它大概2500单位深
Relative to the barn, it's roughly 2,500 units down.
我们需要做的就是将数据输入钻头，
All we need to do is feed this data to the drill,
然后就可以出发了！
and we should be all set!
那么就这样吧！
That's it, then!
任务完成！
Mission accomplished!
好的，团队！
Yeah, team!
太好了
Great.
让我们赶快离开这里吧！
Let's get the heck out of here!
等等，别走！
Wait. Hold on!
这东西上有游戏吗？
Does this thing have any games on it?
不，不，不，不
No, no, no, no.
这不是用来玩的
This wasn't used for games.
唉
Aw.
它之前被用于规划殖民地
It was used for planning the colony.
这里，看！
Here, look!
这是所有建造在
So here's a map of all structures
地球上的建筑的分布图
that were originally built on earth.
说实话，这可能只占
All told, this probably only accounts
原本规划的数量的5%
for maybe 5% of what was originally planned!
原来的计划是什么？
What was the plan?
那么，让我们看一看
Well, let's take a look.
一个建成的地球殖民地！
A finished earth colony!
喔！看这个！
Wow! Look at this!
89个幼儿园，67座尖塔，每个切面一座星际传送台
89 kindergartens, 67 spires, a galaxy warp in each facet,
有效利用一切可用资源
efficient use of all available materials.
你们怎么想的，要停止这个计划？
What were you thinking shutting this operation down!
这本可以很伟大的！
It could have been great!
不，你错了！
No, you're wrong!
你什么意思？
What do you mean?
这多完美，看！
It's perfect. Look at it!
我们就在看啊
We are looking at it.
对，这个计划太臭了！
Yeah, this plan stinks!
完成这个殖民地意味着
Completing this colony would have meant
地球生命的灭绝
the extinction of all life on earth.
但想想它带来的好处-
But think of the good it would have done --
本可制造出的宝石人，
the gems would that would have been made,
我们帝国的扩张！
our empire expanded!
玫瑰石英相信所有的生命都非常宝贵
Rose Quartz believed all life was precious
且值得保护！
and worth protecting!
那么，如果她想保护，
Well, if she wanted to protect it,
那可算是个糟糕的结局啊！
she did a lousy job!
如果地球还是个殖民地就不会有融合簇了！
There'd be no cluster if the earth had stayed a colony!
现在殖民地消失了，地球也不会存来了！
Now there's no colony, and there's gonna be no earth!
真感谢你，玫瑰石英-你毁了这个星球！
So thank you, Rose Quartz -- you doomed the planet!
哦！
Oh!
有什么能够比得上-
♪ Is there anything that's worth more than -- ♪
你给我听着
You listen to me now.
你在谈论一些你丝毫不理解的事情
You are talking about things that you do not understand.
石榴，住手，求你了！
Garnet, stop, please!
这不值得
It's not worth it.
任务完成了
We're done here.
让我们回家吧
Let's just go home.
我说什么了？
What'd I say?!
我只不过在陈述事实而已！
I'm just stating a fact!
叛乱并没有真正拯救地球
The rebellion didn't really save earth.
那只是推迟了不可避免的结局而已
It just delayed the inevitable.
她们不是这么看的
That's not the way they see it.
她们花了几千年时间
They've spent thousands of years
试着保护地球
trying to protect the earth.
我以为也许你最终能理解原因的
I thought maybe you finally understood why.
橄榄石！
Peridot!
干嘛？我来了
What? I'm coming.
赶紧的，你们两个
Let's go, you two.